[The Ingenious One]
[Episode 27: Lianyi Is the Swordswoman]
♫ It's dark but friends are not back ♫
My name is Shu Yanan.
♫ The night breeze can't understand sadness and heartache ♫
Tell me your name too.
Yun Xiang.
♫ Rain falls all night long and I stay awake ♫
♫ The night rain can't conceal the sorrow ♫
♫ Memory is a book ♫
♫ Who wrote all those stories? ♫
♫ Without realizing it ♫
♫ So many years have passed ♫
♫ Flowers fall into the garden ♫
♫ Dear friends, why haven't we met earlier? ♫
♫ Destiny is so cruel ♫
♫ The cloud disperses and mountains are seen ♫
♫ How many old friends are gone? ♫
Leaving me,
♫ I raise my cup to beckon the bright moon. People I miss are thousands of miles away ♫
the day of yesterday would not stay on.
♫ We let go of everything ♫
♫ In the past ♫
♫ Stories take place thousands of miles away ♫
Troubling my mind...
♫ The cloud disperses and mountains are seen ♫
♫ How many old friends are gone? ♫
♫ I raise my cup to beckon the bright moon. People I miss are thousands of miles away ♫
♫ We let go of everything ♫
♫ In the past ♫
♫ Stories take place thousands of miles away ♫
♫ The cloud disperses and mountains are seen ♫
♫ How many old friends are gone? ♫
♫ I raise my cup to beckon the bright moon. People I miss are thousands of miles away ♫
♫ We let go of everything ♫
♫ In the past ♫
♫ Stories take place thousands of miles away ♫
[Shao's Residence]
Your Highness,
you've had a great time
in Nandu.
When are you going back?
Not now. I haven't enjoyed myself to the full.
Besides,
even Father didn't urge me to go back to Yangzhou.
Prince Fu was ordered to meet His Majesty in Beidu.
I'm afraid he doesn't have time to care about you.
I don't care.
Since Father didn't urge me,
you should just leave me alone.
But your words make sense.
Since Father went to Beidu to meet with His Majesty,
I haven't heard from him.
I wonder if someone complained about him again.
I hope His Majesty wouldn't give him a hard time.
His Majesty is wise and benevolent.
Prince Fu is also conscientious.
Your Highness may rest assured.
Everyone wants to be born into a royal family.
They think we're all carefree.
But they are unaware that many complex
and subtle relationships are involved.
People are unpredictable.
One careless move may lead to a tragedy.
Your Highness has lived comfortably since you were young.
I didn't expect you to think of these.
I know because I've seen enough of it.
That's why
I want to learn more from you.
Perhaps I can share Father's burden in the future.
Sir.
Tell me.
What should I do?
I know that you can neither disobey His Majesty's orders
nor betray the benefactor who has brought you new life.
That's indeed a dilemma for you.
But the Princess will eventually figure out
the purpose of our trip.
I beg for your prudence, My Lord.
I will never forget Prince Fu's kindness.
As an imperial guard,
I shall do my best to defend the royal power
and seek peace for the people.
[Imperial Guardsmen Command, To protect His Majesty]
If anyone disobeys His Majesty,
it won't be tolerated
and I shall uphold justice.
We should look for a chance.
No matter what, send Her Highness back first.
She has been naive since she was young.
She shouldn't be involved.
Understood.
Lord Liu.
A man named Yun Xiang is here to see you.
How was it?
Is there any news so soon?
Sir,
I came here to inform you that
our plan needs to be amended.
Go on.
The first deal
may not be completed for the time being.
But the second deal will be finished tonight.
Sir,
undue delay may bring trouble.
I hope you can deploy troops immediately.
What are you panicking about?
We're surrounded by soldiers.
What?
Kou Lianyi is such an idiot.
It's impossible to break through the siege.
I'll distract the soldiers for you.
It's too risky to take the silver certificates
converted with the stolen money along with you.
Give me the silver certificates.
If I can't be back anymore,
Young Master,
please don't forget Yuewu.
Uncle.
Whom are we here to arrest?
You'll know soon.
Let's go.
It looks like the person has lived here for a few days.
Sir, one has escaped.
Watch your step!
Get out of the way!
There...
Go!
Search!
Master asked me to inform you
that blood must be atoned for with blood.
With just you?
Let's go.
Wait for me here.
Uncle.
Uncle!
Uncle, help me!
How dare you use the Princess as bait?
It happened suddenly. I...
Stop quibbling!
Uncle,
it's not Li Bo's fault.
It was my idea.
You're not allowed to go anywhere else tomorrow.
Just stay with the Princess in the courtyard.
Calm down.
Please don't be mad at me anymore.
Consider it a small gift to compensate you.
I really like your outfit today.
This is exactly as the saying goes, "Feminine charm concealing chivalry,
tenderness veiling a jade sword's blade."
People from the Yuntai Sect are forbidden to fall in love.
Perhaps I was already defeated
when we first met in Baiju Town.
I hope all of this can end soon.
I want to stay with you like this forever
and not care about the chaos outside.
Master.
Miss Ke.
Look at the dress.
Is it of top quality?
She only wore it once.
Why don't we give it to Tianhu?
That's right.
How could Tianhu wear other people's old clothes?
Throw these away.
Master.
Dingyuan Pill.
It's so precious
that it's hard to buy but cures all poisons.
I'll give it to Ten Taels of Gold.
By the way, Miss Ke,
her leaving is also beneficial to you.
The house you're living in down there is too small.
From now on, you'll move up here
and live in this room.
I mean it.
All right, I'm tired today.
I'm now going back to have some rest.
Please don't disturb me.
Also, please go to Mingyu
and tell him to go to Guanghui Bank
and meet Mr. Mo tomorrow morning.
Mr. Mo,
why do you keep sighing today?
I've never seen you like this.
I've been keeping a low profile all my life.
That was the only secret I had,
but Yun Xiang revealed it all.
We need to verify the authenticity of the tributary cloth later.
It's better for me to do it.
Mr. Mo,
how did you find out the whereabouts of the tributary cloth?
Don't ask anything you shouldn't.
Rest assured.
I know what to
and what not to say later.
That's good.
If this matter is exposed,
not only will I be beheaded,
but your Su family will also suffer a lot.
Whom are we meeting with today?
Fine, I won't ask anymore.
Remember, don't talk as you wish.
Understood.
Please.
How many do you have?
I'll take them all.
You didn't even inquire about the price.
I can afford it.
Come again tomorrow.
Wait.
I have to ask
where the goods came from.
According to the rules of our business,
we don't question the source of the goods.
I've known Guan for years.
Even if I ask a question, it's no big deal.
I'll ask you one last time.
Where did you get the goods?
No problem. I'll fulfil your wishes.
What kind of a fool
would be looking for trouble here?
Isn't this Mr. Mo?
Guan.
How have you been?
Come on.
Stop beating around the bush.
Do you really want the goods
or do you have other intentions?
Fine, I'll cut to the chase.
I do have another purpose.
I want to know who owns the goods
and where those people are.
Can you let me into the details?
I didn't want to take over the hot potato.
It's hard to get rid of it.
Only the royal members of the Japanese dare to accept it.
But you know how stingy those Japanese are.
But now that I think about it, it's a business without cost.
So I bit the bullet.
A business without cost?
That means someone used the goods
as a pledge.
Did they come over to you?
Mo,
don't force me to break the rules.
You may have outsmarted yourself.
I think Master Guan has
only hundreds of bolts of tributary cloth.
If you agree to hand them over,
I promise to sell you
5,000 bolts at a low price in a year.
How arrogant you are!
You offered 5,000 bolts of tributary cloth without hesitation.
With that arrogance,
are you from the Su family in Nandu?
Judging from your age,
are you the second son of the Su family?
Great. You came at a good time.
Thank you for the gift, Mr. Mo.
I'll let my fellows down if I don't accept it.
Guan, listen.
Don't...
Master Guan.
How much do you want after kidnapping me?
Let me put it this way.
I'm not only the second son of the Su family
but also the chairman of the entire Nandu Chamber of Commerce.
It turns out that I'm more valuable than you thought.
Interesting.
I've never seen a hostage
raise the price for himself.
If you cooperate with me,
I'm sure I can double the profit
Mr. Mo promised you.
Okay, see you.
Come on. Let's go.
Mr. Mo, why didn't you tell me earlier that we were meeting the pirates?
We were just here to inquire.
I didn't expect you to be so impulsive.
Are you really going to work with Guan?
Let's get out of the gate alive first.
Besides, if they really want to cooperate with the Su family,
they must kidnap me again.
The pirates
have no future at all.
I don't mind giving them an empty promise.
You have indeed learned a lot from Yun Xiang.
You'll perform well as the chairman in the future.
A strong general does not lead weak soldiers.
An accomplished master has no unqualified disciples.
By the way, Mr. Mo,
do you know what's wrong with Yun recently?
What's wrong with him?
He seems to be mad at Miss Shu.
In the past, even if they had disputes,
they wouldn't be like this.
Miss Shu is acting weird too.
There's something behind everything she says lately.
It's like saying goodbye.
Saying goodbye?
Please help me ask him
to come to Guanghui Bank as soon as possible.
Mr. Yun.
I've prepared hangover soup for you.
Please get up and have some.
Hangover soup?
You should prepare wine for me to get sober.
Go and get it.
If you have something on your mind,
you can pour it out to me.
It's not a good idea to drown your sorrows in drinks.
I've been doing well lately.
I have no sorrows at all.
Leave it to me.
You're back so soon.
The wine is good, Yun.
Unfortunately,
it's a pity that you had such a wonderful time
but not a beautiful lady by your side.
Listen.
Jin has called Tianhu
to go to Jishan Hall.
Yet you are pestering Menglan every day.
Are you still going to operate Liansheng House?
Listen, I'm also one of the owners.
Go ahead and manage your business.
Leave me alone.
You're occupying my place.
Aren't you afraid that Miss Shu will return and get even with you?
Or she won't come back anymore?
Do you still remember what you said
when I was trapped in love?
Why are you so helpless
when it comes to yourself?
I'm different from you.
How?
Forget it.
Even you can't figure it out,
let alone me.
But you need to get up quickly.
Mr. Mo asked you to go there as soon as possible.
Have you found the tributary cloth?
Yes.
The soldiers used the tributary cloth as a pledge
to become pirates under Master Guan.
But I've made a deal with them.
Master Guan promised to hand over the soldiers.
It tastes so bad. That's it.
Yun.
I won't ask about you and Miss Shu.
But when you want a drink, can you invite me?
I'm always at your disposal.
You won't tell me if I don't ask, will you?
How dare you hide it from me for so long?
Yun Xiang knows everything about me.
He's already obsessed with Shu Yanan.
Who knows what he told her?
Since you're sure
she's from the Lingyuan Sect,
how could you let her go?
Uncle, I...
I begged Kang
to hide it for me.
You have been drinking my wine since you came.
Say something.
How much did you tell her?
I told her everything I could
and couldn't say.
Look at you.
You are reluctant for her to leave.
You joined the Yuntai Sect in your teens
and studied in the mountains for 15 years.
But you still fell for beauties after leaving the mountain.
However, it's not your fault.
I yearn so much...
To tie her back and be with her forever.
Forget it.
Love is ruthless.
You are that calculative,
but you didn't expect you couldn't get over the unattainable love.
Anyway,
if that girl really works for Lingyuan,
then the one stopping you two
will be the hundred-year grudge between Lingyuan and Yuntai.
I know.
I don't hate her for being a member of the Lingyuan Sect.
So what if she lied to me?
Even if she ends up killing me,
it's better than
leaving without saying goodbye.
It's fine that you tell me that.
But you should keep her in your heart only, from now on.
There are some words
I only dare to say to you.
It's somehow hilarious.
If you hadn't been that conscientious,
I wouldn't have been so close to you.
Forget it. Let's change our thinking.
You asked me to...
You asked me to help you locate
the whereabouts of the soldiers on the towboat.
What are you planning?
The Tang family's property
is already in your pocket.
Really?
[Lingyuan, Kou Lianyi]
Where is Bi Yuewu?
I'm asking why you are here alone.
My dear sister.
Are you surprised that I managed to escape?
What?
The moment you left,
we were surrounded by the shadowmen.
More soldiers came in less than an hour.
Can you tell now?
Yun Xiang has never trusted you.
I wonder how many times
he used you all this time.
Didn't Bi Yuewu manage to escape?
If she hadn't distracted the pursuers,
I wouldn't have escaped so easily.
Immediately cross the river and report this to Mother.
I'll go back to the city to gather the information.
Maybe I can save her.
No need.
She must have already died.
She made a lot of contributions to our sect.
Are you going to leave her in danger?
Her life was used to redeem mine.
She has served her proper purpose.
There's no need for you to take another risk.
She has been with you for seven years.
That's right. I've got tired of her.
Bi Yuewu was in trouble because of you.
If we weren't related by blood,
I wouldn't stop you.
Go if you want to sign your own death warrant.
No one cares about you.
Yuanjie,
when did you become so heartless?
If you are that soft-hearted,
how can you be the master of the sect?
Let's go.
We can't stay in Nandu anymore.
Mother will also blame me when we go back.
Set sail.
Set sail!
Mr. Nangong.
Young Master Kou.
Lady Kou.
Why aren't you eating?
Mother,
are you angry?
What rights do I have to be so?
I am already on tenterhooks
to have dinner with the three of you.
How dare I be angry?
Madam Kou,
we can't afford that.
You're too modest.
I'm honoured
to have dinner with you.
Did you send Yuan Ye,
who was under Ye Xiao, to me?
Madam Kou,
since he had my token,
of course, he was ordered by me.
Talk nicely.
Yuan Ye told me a story
that happened in Nandu.
I couldn't tell if it was true.
So I could only ask you to make the final call.
Yes, he told me
my useless children
got the Yuntai Sect and the government
to kill Mr. Ye.
It's ridiculous if they harmed our people using other forces.
Maybe he was so eager to protect his master
that he talked that nonsense.
I've already executed him.
Madam Kou is indeed wise.
One threw herself at someone from the Yuntai Sect,
and the other was keen to do the dirty business.
How about you kill me first
and fight for the position of master?
What do you think?
Mother, we are aware of our mistakes.
Call me Madam Kou.
Yes, Madam Kou.
I am too incompetent
to discipline you two,
that's why you caused the trouble.
Mr. Nangong,
do you know how to punish them?
Madam Kou, this is your family matter.
I shouldn't intervene in it.
I'm asking you about how to deal with them.
In my opinion,
Lady Kou approached the Yuntai's disciple
to learn more about the enemy.
There's no point in punishing her.
Young Master Kou stole official silver
for the benefit of our sect.
It's just that he didn't plan well.
Enough with your false display of affection.
How dare you!
Mother.
Madam Kou.
I am aware that revolution
will surely arouse the fellows' resentment.
It's just a matter of time.
Although the situation in Nandu City is still unclear,
the Yangzhou merchants
are already under Lingyuan's control.
How about I transfer my business to Young Master Kou
so that I can have a carefree life?
Don't speak with sarcasm.
- I don't care about your money.
- Yuanjie.
Mother.
From now on,
you are not allowed to use the Young Master's seal.
Return to Jiangbei immediately.
You can't cross the river without my order.
All of you, leave.
Yes, madam.
Lianyi, stay here.
Do you still remember your last name
and whose daughter you are?
I dare not forget it, not even a day.
Since you haven't forgotten,
why did you leave home and go to the South?
You even swore that
you could find a good way to deal with Nangong Fang.
Is the current situation what you want?
You both think I'm an old fool
who didn't notice Nangong Fang's ulterior motive.
Are you cold?
No.
It's cold by the water.
Mother, it's okay.
Listen to me.
I'm afraid you'll catch a cold.
I will protect you both no matter how old I am.
I always turn a blind eye
to Nangong Fang
and let him do what he wants
and outshine the others.
Do you know why?
You have no choice.
Elaborate it.
A sturdy tree will be cut down, a strong army will be annihilated.
In order to restore the throne,
Lingyuan fought for almost a century.
I'm afraid before you became the master...
Go ahead.
The sect had almost been doomed.
If you didn't accommodate to circumstances,
I'm afraid we wouldn't have been able to survive till today.
Not to mention standing above all in Jiangbei
and fighting with Jiangnan.
Who do you think contributed to this?
Mother is good at discerning people and using people.
But Nangong Fang did contribute a lot.
In this case,
you can only watch Nangong Fang
expand his territory every day
until it's hard to control.
Now the power of Jiangnan seems to be under the Lingyuan Sect,
but he's already in control of it.
That's one of the reasons.
Second, the mountains of Lingyuan are all over the country.
Every mountain needs money and food.
Without him,
who would support the food and accommodation of over 10,000 people?
He said he wanted to hand over
the business in Jiangnan to Yuanjie.
If you were him, would you dare?
What should we do?
Whoever controls Jiangnan
is working for Lingyuan.
As long as he can be of use to Ling Yuan,
there is no harm in using him.
I was right about you.
You should know that Lingyuan doesn't belong to the Kou family.
If one day I'm gone,
and you have no means of suppressing him,
he will not spare your lives.
Yuanjie is brave and smart
but too arrogant.
On the contrary, you are gifted
and meticulous.
You must assist Yuanjie in the future.
If Yuanjie takes over the position of master,
you have to take over the position of Nangong Fang.
If so,
I'm afraid you'll be disappointed.
Why?
Nangong Fang has different means from Lingyuan,
but the same as Yuntai's.
I'd been observing
the people of Yuntai in Nandu
about how they plan and set up.
But I was always slow in understanding.
I couldn't figure out
or learn their essence.
There's no need to learn from Yun Xiang.
I want you to follow Nangong Fang back to Nandu
and see how he can deal with the people of Yuntai.
Have you forgotten
why I left home and went south back then?
The engagement has been broken off.
I want you to keep an eye on him
and learn from him by his side.
That way, you can deal with him one day.
But Nangong Fang
will see through you.
If I give him the order,
he won't dare decline.
I'm old now.
There's not much I can do for you.
Don't let me down.